-=TLF字幕组=- 荣誉出品
翻译：Jason Lee
翻译：诗琪
翻译：海的风
君临
King's Landing
翻译： lydia萌
校对：Lord Vader
统筹：饭离烨
特效：离太阳只有七步
卡林湾
Moat Cailin
临冬城
WinterFell
绝境长城
The Wall
布拉佛斯
Braavos
弥林
Meereen
根据乔治·R·R·马丁著《冰与火之歌》改编
权力的游戏
第四季   第十集
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
电视剧编剧
戴维·贝尼奥夫 & D·B·威斯
导演
亚历克斯·格拉维斯
森林之子
You're wearing a black cloak again.
你又披上黑斗篷了
I've been sent to negotiate with you.
我被派来与你方谈判
It appears my trusting nature got the better of me.
看来我对你的信任占了上风
It's happened before.
之前信过你一次
I was hoping your loyalty was real
我曾希望你忠心耿耿
when you pledged yourself to us, Jon Snow.
你曾向我们起誓，琼恩·雪诺
Truly I was.
我真希望如此
The Halfhand ordered me to join your army
断掌科林命令我加入你方
and bring back whatever information I could to Castle Black.
把有用的情报带回黑城堡
He made me kill him so you'd trust me.
他命令我杀了他，换取你们的信任
I was loyal...
我是忠心耿耿的…
to him and to my Night's Watch vows.
忠于他的命令和守夜人誓言
All your vows?
你所有的誓言吗？
She wasn't enough to turn you, eh?
她不忍心背叛你，对吗？
Were you enough to turn her?
你忍心背叛她？
She put three arrows in me
我逃跑时
when I escaped.
她射中了我三箭
Did you see her again at Castle Black?
你在黑城堡又见过她吗？
- Yes. - And?
- 见过
- 然后呢？
She's dead.
她死了
- Your doing? - No.
- 你下的手？
- 不是
We'll drink to her.
我们敬她一杯
Of all the ways I'd kill you,
要你命的方式有千万种
poison would be the last.
可我不会下毒
- Ygritte. - Ygritte.
- 敬耶哥蕊特
That's not wine.
这不是酒
No, it's a proper northern drink, Jon Snow.
对，这是正统北方饮品，琼恩·雪诺
You did well. Fought hard.
你干得不错，以死相搏
Killed some of our strongest men.
杀了我的几个大汉
One of our giants went into your tunnel
我方的一个巨人进入了隧道
and never came out again.
就再也没出来过
Mag the Mighty.
强壮的玛格
He's dead.
他死了
He killed my friend Grenn.
他杀了我的朋友葛兰
He was their king.
玛格是他们的王
The last of a bloodline that stretches back
巨人族的最后血脉，这可以追溯到
before the First Men.
早于先民的年代
Grenn came from a farm.
葛兰出身农家
- Mag and Grenn. - Grenn and Mag.
- 敬玛格和葛兰
- 敬葛兰和玛格
Kullback, could I trouble you for something to eat?
库尔贝克，能给我们弄点儿吃的吗？
I don't imagine our guest has eaten anything
我猜咱们客人没吃过东西
for quite some time.
饿很久了
So, you're here to strike a bargain?
那么，你来是想谈和？
Turn your army around and go home.
叫你的军队掉头回家吧
You know I know you're low on arrows,
我知道你们的箭所剩无多
you're low on oil, you're low on men.
火油也没多少，人手也寥寥无几
How many are left, 50?
有几个剩下的，五十个？
I told Tormund and Orell.
我告诉了托蒙德和欧瑞尔
We have more than 1,000 men.
我们有超过一千人
I showed you everything I had.
我让你见识一下我的储备
The whole army, 100,000 strong.
全军十万之众
And what did you do?
你们又能做什么？
You fired on us with everything you had.
你们拼上所有的储备与我们交战
It wasn't much. As soon as I saw that,
这些又算什么？我一望便知
I sent 400 men to climb the Wall,
派了四百人爬长城
an unmanned stretch five miles west of here.
先行部队向西延伸五里
A lot of them will die climbing,
许多人不慎摔死
but most of them will be over by the end of the day.
但一天下来有更多的人前赴后继
It's me being honest with you, Jon Snow,
<i>和你开诚布公的可是我</i>
which is more than you've ever done for me.
<i>你的所作所为和这比起来算什么？</i>
My people have bled enough.
我的人民付出了足够的代价
We're not here to conquer.
我们不是来这儿讨伐的
We're here to hide behind your Wall.
而是需要越过长城躲避严冬
Just like you. We need your tunnel.
正如你们一样，我们需要隧道
Now we both know that winter is coming.
我们都清楚凛冬将至
And if my people aren't south of the Wall when it comes in earnest,
如果我们子民无法藏身于长城以南
we'll all end up worse than dead.
那么我们要比冻死还惨
You want to strike a bargain with me?
你要与我谈和吗？
Here's the bargain.
这就是我的条件
You go back, you open the gates to us,
你回去，打开大门
and I swear to you that no one else will die.
我向你保证不会再有人死
Refuse,
如果拒绝
and we'll kill every last man at Castle Black.
我们会把黑城堡杀个片甲不留
Ah!
啊！
Oh, that's why you're here.
你原来就是这个企图
I reckon you could do it before any of them could stop you.
我猜你可以在他们反应过来得手吧
They'd kill you, of course.
他们当然会宰了你
They'd kill you slow.
让你慢慢地死
But you knew that when you came in here.
不过你来这里之前就心知肚明了
Are you capable of that, Jon Snow?
你有这能耐吗，琼恩·雪诺？
Killing a man in his own tent when he's just offered you peace?
在我自己的帐篷里杀了我，而我现在正跟你谈和？
Is that what the Night's Watch is?
这就是守夜人的为人吗？
Is that what you are?
那就是你的为人吗？
Riders coming!
<i>有骑兵！</i>
- Are you attacking us? - No.
- 你们在向我们进攻吗？
- 不
It's like you said, we don't have the men.
如你所说，我们没有人手
Hold! To me! To me!
稳住阵脚！在我周围！
Stand down!
原地站住！
I said my people have bled enough
我说过我的子民付出了太多代价
and I meant it.
绝无戏言
Round them up.
<i>把他们都绑起来！</i>
Stay with the horses.
<i>和马匹呆在一起</i>
You're the King-beyond-the-Wall?
你就是塞外之王？
- Do you know who I am? - Never had the pleasure.
- 你认识我？
- 尚未谋面
This is Stannis Baratheon,
此乃史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩
the one true king of the Seven Kingdoms.
七大王国之真命天子
We're not in the Seven Kingdoms and you're not dressed for this weather.
我们可不是七国疆域，你穿的也不是这个季节的行头
It is customary to kneel when surrendering to a king.
战败一方向国王屈膝拜倒乃理所当然之礼仪
We do not kneel.
我们不跪
I'll have thousands of your men in chains by nightfall,
天黑时，你方数千人将被囚禁
have nowhere to put them, have nothing to feed them.
无处收容，无衣无食
I'm not here to slaughter beat dogs.
我们不是来屠杀丧家之犬的
Their fate depends on their king.
他们的命运取决于他们的王
All the same, we do not kneel.
没什么区别，我们不跪
Take these men away.
把他们带走
What's a man of the Night's Watch doing in a wildling camp?
你这个守夜人在蛮族军队里凑什么热闹？
I was sent to discuss terms with the King-beyond-the-Wall.
我被指派来与塞外之王谈和
You're speaking to the one true king, boy.
和你说话的才是真正的国王，小子
You will address him as Your Grace.
你要称呼“陛下”才是
I know he's the king. My father died for him.
我知道他是国王，我父亲因他而死
My name is Jon Snow, Your Grace.
我叫琼恩·雪诺，陛下
I'm Ned Stark's son.
奈德·史塔克之子
Your father was an honorable man.
你父亲是个高尚的人
He was, Your Grace.
是的，陛下
What do you think he'd have done with him?
你认为他会如何处置此人？
I was this man's prisoner once.
我曾是他的阶下囚
He could have tortured me. He could have killed me.
他本可以折磨我，本可以杀了我
But he spared my life.
<i>但他饶我一命</i>
I think my father would have taken him prisoner,
若父亲在世，会把他送进监狱
listened to what he had to say.
听听他要说什么
Very well, then. Take him.
很好，把他带走
Your Grace.
陛下
If my father had seen the things that I've seen,
<i>如果父亲能看到我所看到的</i>
he'd also tell you to burn the dead before nightfall.
他也会让你在黄昏前烧了尸体
All of them.
全部尸体
I would suggest milk of the poppy
我建议用罂粟汁
to ease his pain, but he is completely insensate.
来帮他止痛，但他毫无知觉
Bloody Martells.
残忍的马泰尔家族
The cause appears to be manticore venom.
看样子是中了狮身蝎尾兽毒
It is. The Death's Head manticore.
是的，死神的头等狮身蝎尾兽
Yes, I've read a great deal about it.
我读过有关它的很多资料
It's a horrible poison.
真是种可怕的毒药
Usually Mantari in origin.
通常起源于曼塔利
Oh! Yes, yes.
哦！是啊
There's nothing to be done.
无药可救了
Yes, there is.
不，还有救
May I ask what you think you're doing?
你在这儿干什么
Saving him.
救他
Your Grace, I wish it were otherwise,
殿下，我也希望不至于此
but Ser Gregor is beyond saving.
但格雷果爵士真的无药可救
Well, well beyond.
无药可救
This man is not even a maester,
这人连个学士都不是
let alone Grand Maester.
更别提大学士了
That's for the best.
那样最好不过
No maester knows how to save him.
学士不会知道怎么救他
That is exactly the sort of arrogance
殿下，正是如此傲慢自大
that had him expelled from the Citadel, Your Grace.
他才被赶出大学城
His curiosity was deemed dangerous and unnatural.
他好奇于危险和非自然的东西
Rightly so, in my opinion.
我觉得这么处置他挺恰当
You're dismissed, Grand Maester.
大学士，你可以退下了
But, Your Grace, this is my laboratory.
但是殿下，这可是我实验室
- Not anymore. - But I--
- 不再是了
<i>- 但是我…</i>
- You can save him? - Difficult to say, Your Grace.
- 你能救活他吗？
- 陛下，还不好说
But if my past work is any guide...
<i>不过以我过去的经验来看</i>
...we stand a chance.
还有机会
Do everything you can.
竭尽全力救他
Come to me for anything you need.
有什么需要尽管告诉我
Thank you, Your Grace.
谢谢殿下
You should know,
<i>但你得知道</i>
the process may change him...
这个过程会改变他…
somewhat.
些许
Will it weaken him?
会把他变弱吗？
Oh, no.
那不会
Very well, then.
那就好
Not another word.
<i>别再说了</i>
We've been over this. The matter's closed.
我们已经商量完了
I'm opening it again.
我还要继续商量
You were betrothed to Loras Tyrell.
你跟洛拉斯·提利尔订婚了
You're still betrothed to Loras Tyrell.
这事板上钉钉
And you will marry Loras Tyrell
你会嫁给他
as soon as Tommen marries Margaery.
很快托曼也会娶玛格丽
I will not.
我不会嫁
Jaime cannot marry or inherit lands.
詹姆不会娶妻，也不会继承领土
Tyrion's sentence will be carried out tomorrow.
提利昂的判决明天执行
You have on several occasions made great claims
你已多次为对这个家族的未来…
about your commitment to this family's future.
表达了自己的承诺
Your role in that future
你现在的角色…
is more vital now than it ever was.
比任何时候都至关重要
I don't care.
我不管
I will stay in King's Landing where I belong with my son the king.
我要留在君临城，在我儿子，国王的身边
When you were nine years old, I was called to the capital.
你还9岁时，我就被召到王城
I decided to take your brother with me and not you.
我当时决定带你哥哥随行，不带你
You insisted that you would not be left at Casterly Rock
你坚持无论如何
under any circumstances. And if you recall--
不愿再留在凯岩城，如果你还记得…
I'm not interested in hearing another one of your smug stories
我没兴趣再听你那自以为是的故事
about the time you won.
每次你都赢了
This isn't going to be one of those times.
这次你不会再赢
Do you think you'll be the first person
你觉得你是第一个…
dragged into a sept to be married against her will?
被迫结婚的人吗？
When you marched into the throne room to tell me
当你走进宫殿告诉我…
we'd won the Battle of Blackwater-- do you remember?
我们赢了黑水河之战，还记得吗？
I was sitting on the Iron Throne with Tommen.
我当时正跟托曼一同坐在铁宝座上
I was about to give him essence of nightshade.
准备喂他龙葵
That's how far I was willing to go when I thought
一想起有个邪恶的人要夺走我的儿子
someone awful had come to take my son away.
这么出格的事我也做得出
Someone awful is coming to take him away.
这个邪恶的人即将来把他夺走
- No. - Joffrey is dead.
- 不
- 乔佛里已经死了
Myrcella's been sold like livestock.
弥赛菈像个牲畜一样被卖了
And now you want to ship me off to Highgarden and steal my boy.
现在你要把我送到高庭，偷走我的儿子
My last boy.
我最后一个儿子
Margaery will dig her claws in,
玛格丽会伸出魔爪…
you will dig your claws in and you'll fight over him
你也会伸出魔爪像野兽一样与她厮打
like beasts until you rip him apart.
直到你们把他撕成两半
I will burn our house to the ground before I let that happen.
我把家烧了，也不能让这种事情发生
And how will you do that?
你要怎么做？
I'll tell everyone the truth.
我要告诉每个人真相
What truth would that be?
<i>那是个什么真相？</i>
You don't know, do you?
你还不知道吗？
You never believed it.
你从来都不信
How is that possible?
那怎么可能呢，是吗？
What am I saying? Of course it's possible.
怎么说呢？那当然是可能的
How can someone so consumed by the idea of his family
你怎么会如此沉迷于家族观念
have any conception what his actual family was doing?
连自己家人发生了什么都不关心？
We were right there in front of you and you didn't see us.
我们就在你眼皮底下，你却没发现
One look in the past 20 years,
回首过去20年
one real look at your own children and you would have known.
要是你仔细看看自己的孩子就能发现
Known what?
发现什么？
Everything they say is true.
他们说的都是真的
- About Jaime and me. - No.
- 有关詹姆和我的事
- 不
- Your legacy is a lie. - No, no, no, no.
- 你的后裔竟个骗局
- 不，不，不是真的
I don't believe you.
我不相信
Yes, you do.
你当然相信
Jaime.
詹姆
You won.
你赢了
One fewer brother. Must be proud of yourself.
又少个弟弟，你很得意啊
There's really nothing you wouldn't do, is there?
你真不择手段，是吗？
For my family, no, nothing.
为了我的家族，是的
I would do things for my family you couldn't imagine.
我能做到你无法想象的事
- Tyrion is your family. - He's not.
- 提利昂是你的家人
- 他不是
- You don't get to choose. - I do. So do you.
- 这你无从选择
- 我能，你也能
You can choose the creature that killed our mother to come into this world--
你都能选择那个怪物
那怪物杀死了带他来到人世的母亲
Are you really mad enough to blame him for that?
你疯了吗，居然为那事责备他？
He didn't decide to kill her. He was an infant.
<i>他没有决定杀她</i>
<i>他只是个婴儿</i>
A disease doesn't decide to kill you.
疾病并没有决定杀人
All the same, you cut it out before it does.
但你还是要消灭它
What do you decide? What do you choose?
你决定了什么？你选择了什么？
The things I did to get back to you,
我回来是为找你
to endure all that, only to find you--
承受一切，我只要找到你
I choose you.
我选择了你
- Those are words. - Yes.
- 说说而已
- 是的
Like the ones I just said to Father.
就像我对父亲说的那些话一样
I told him.
我告诉了他
Told him what?
告诉他什么？
I told him about us.
我把我们的事告诉了他
You told him?
你告诉他了？
I told him I won't marry Loras Tyrell.
我告诉他我不会嫁给洛拉斯·提利尔
I told him I'm staying right here with Tommen, with you.
我告诉他，我就要在这跟托曼和你在一起
You think he'll just accept that?
你觉得他能接受吗？
Go and ask him.
去问问他
What did you say?
你说什么了？
I don't want to talk about Tywin Lannister.
我不想谈泰温·兰尼斯特
I don't choose Tywin Lannister.
我没有选择他
I don't love Tywin Lannister.
我不爱他
I love my brother.
我爱我的弟弟
I love my lover.
我爱我的情人
People will whisper, they'll make their jokes.
人们会窃窃私语，嘲笑我们
Let them.
让他们说去吧
They're all so small, I can't even see them.
他们太渺小了，我都不会注意
I only see what matters.
我只注意对我重要的事
Someone will walk in.
有人会进来的
I don't care.
我不管
你面前是“风暴降生”丹妮莉丝
不焚者
弥林的女王
安达尔人，洛伊拿人和先民的女王
大草海的卡丽熙
奴隶解放者和龙之母
谢谢你接见我，陛下
我叫芬尼斯
I can speak the common tongue if you wish.
如果你想的话我可以说通用语
You speak it very well.
你说得非常好
Before you freed me, I belonged to Master Mighdal.
在你解放我前，我属于米格德尔主人
I was tutor to his children.
我是他孩子们的导师
I taught them languages and history.
<i>我教他们语言和历史</i>
They know a great deal about your family because of me.
因为我，他们知道了很多关于你的家族
Little Calla is only seven,
<i>小卡拉只有七岁</i>
but she admires you very much.
但是她很崇拜你
I hope I can prove worthy of her admiration.
希望我能证明配得上她的崇拜
What can I do for you?
我能为你做什么？
When you took the city, the children begged me
你夺下城市的时候，孩子们请求我
not to leave the house.
不要离开房子
But Master Mighdal and I agreed that I must.
但是米格德尔大人和我觉得必须走
So I lost my home.
然后我失去了我的家
Now I live on the streets.
现在我无家可归
I have outfitted mess halls
我已经供应食物
to feed all former slaves and barracks to shelter them.
给以前的奴隶并建棚屋给他们住
I do not mean to offend, Your Grace.
我无意冒犯，陛下
I went to one of these places.
<i>我去过这些地方中的一个</i>
The young prey on the old.
年轻的掠夺年老的
Take what they want and beat us if we resist.
拿走他们想要的，如果反抗还殴打我们
My Unsullied will make them safe again in short order,
我的无垢者很快就能保证他们的安全
my friend, this I promise you.
我的朋友，我向你保证
Even if they are safe, who would I be there?
即使安全了，在那里我又是谁
What purpose would I serve?
我存在的意义是什么
With my master, I was a teacher.
<i>在主人那，我是一个老师</i>
I had the respect and love of his children.
他的孩子们尊重我，爱戴我
What is it that you want from me?
那你想要我做什么？
Your Grace, I ask you
陛下，我请求你
to let me sell myself back to Master Mighdal.
让我回到米格德尔大人那里
You want to return to a man who owned you
你想回到一个拥有你的人旁边
like a goat or a chair?
像一只山羊或一把椅子
Please, Your Grace.
请求您，陛下
The young may rejoice in the new world you have built for them,
年轻人会在你为他们建立的新世界里感到欣喜
but for those of us too old to change,
但是对于我们这些冥顽不灵的人
there is only fear and squalor.
只有恐惧和肮脏
I am not alone.
我不是一个人
There are many outside waiting to beg the same of you.
有很多人在外面有同样请求…
I did not take this city to preside
我夺取此城，消灭不公正
over the injustice I fought to destroy.
不能让其继续当道
I took it to bring people freedom.
我夺取此城是为了给人们带来自由
But freedom means making your own choices.
但自由意味着做出你们自己的选择
I will allow you to sign a contract with your former master.
我会同意你和你的前主人签一个合同
It may not cover a period lasting longer than a year.
它的时效不能超过一年
Thank you, Your Grace.
谢谢，陛下
Thank you.
谢谢
The masters will take advantage of this situation.
奴隶主们会利用这种情况
The men serving them
服侍他们的人
will be slaves in all but name.
行奴隶之实，而无其名
Approach, my friend.
靠近点，我的朋友
我不明白，女王
陛下说你可以靠近点
I have brought you--
<i>我带来了</i>
He came from the sky.
他从天上飞来
The black one.
<i>黑色的</i>
The winged shadow.
翅膀的阴影
He came from the sky and...
<i>他从天上来然后…</i>
My girl.
<i>我的女儿</i>
My little girl.
我的小女儿
What was her name?
<i>她叫什么名字？</i>
Zala, Your Grace.
<i>萨拉，陛下</i>
- How old was she? - Three.
- 她多大？
- ３岁
Three.
3岁
没有龙的消息吗？
有水手看到他3天前飞过黑崖，女王陛下
之后没消息了
在地下墓穴等我
They came to us from White Harbor and Barrowton,
<i>他们加入我们，从白港到荒冢屯</i>
from Fairmarket and King's Landing,
从美人市集到君临
from north and south,
从北方到南方
from east and west.
从东方到西方
They died protecting men, women, and children
他们为保护男人、女人和孩子而死
who will never know their names.
那些永远不会知道他们名字的人
It is for us to remember them.
<i>我们要记住他们</i>
Our brothers,
<i>我们的兄弟</i>
we shall never see their like again.
<i>我们永远不会遇到他们那样的人</i>
And now their watch is ended.
现在他们的守望结束了
Your old blind man patched me up.
你们那个老瞎子帮我包扎
Why?
<i>为什么</i>
He's sworn to treat all wounded men, friend or foe.
他发誓善待所有的伤者，无论朋友还是敌人
You want me alive so you can torture me?
你们想让我活着然后来折磨我
No one's gonna torture you.
没有人会折磨你
So how do we die? Hanging? Beheading?
那我们会怎么死？绞死？砍头？
Drop us from the top of the Wall?
<i>从城墙的顶端扔下来?</i>
I don't know what happens to the prisoners.
我不知道会怎么处理囚犯
Who decides?
谁决定？
I suppose Stannis does.
应该是史坦尼斯
He your king now?
他现在是你的王了
I don't have a king.
我没有王
You spent too much time with us, Jon Snow.
你和我们呆太久了，琼恩·雪诺
You can never be a kneeler again.
你不会再下跪了
We're gonna burn the bodies of your dead.
我们要焚烧你们的尸体
Do you want to say any words over them?
有什么要对他们说吗？
Words? What kind of words?
说话？说什么话？
Funeral words. I don't know how the free folk do it.
葬礼的话，我不知道自由民是怎么做的
Do what?
<i>做什么？</i>
Say farewell.
告别
The dead can't hear us, boy.
死人听不到我们，小子
Snow.
雪诺
Did you love her?
你爱过她吗？
She loved you.
她爱着你
She told you?
她告诉你了？
No.
<i>没有</i>
All she ever talked about was killing you.
她不停说要杀了你
That's how I know.
<i>这就是我怎么知道的</i>
She belongs in the North.
她属于北方
The real North.
<i>真正的北方</i>
You understand me?
明白我的意思吗？
We can stop. We can rest.
停下来，休息
We'll rest with the three-eyed raven.
没找到三眼乌鸦不休息
We're not going to make it.
我们到不了了
We're already here.
我们已经到了
Jojen.
<i>玖健</i>
Look, Jojen. Look.
看，玖健，看
Jojen! Come on!
玖健，快点
Help them! Now!
帮他们，快点
Hold on to me!
<i>抓着我</i>
Hang on!
坚持住
- Hodor. - Help them!
- 阿多
- 帮他们
Hodor.
阿多
Hodor!
Hodor.
阿多
Hodor!
Bran!
<i>布兰</i>
Save yourself, now!
救你自己，快点
Come with me, Brandon Stark.
<i>跟我来，布兰登·史塔克</i>
He is lost.
他没救了
Come with me or die with him.
跟我来或者和他一起死
Go with them.
跟他们走
They cannot follow us.
<i>他们进不来</i>
The power that moves them is powerless here.
控制它们的力量在这里会失效
Who are you?
你是谁？
The First Men called us the children,
先民叫我们森林之子
but we were born long before them.
但是我们出生比他们久远
Come, he waits for you.
来，他在等你
You're the three-eyed raven?
你就是三眼乌鸦
I've been many things.
我的形态很多
Now I am what you see.
现在是你看到的样子
My brother, he led us to you and now he--
我的弟弟，他带我们来找你而现在他
He knew what would happen.
他知道会发生什么
From the moment he left,
从他出发的那一刻
he knew and he went anyway.
他知道，但还是来了
How do you know?
你怎么知道？
I've been watching you.
我一直在看着你们
All of you.
每个人
All of your lives.
每个人的生活
With 1,000 eyes and one.
用我一千零一只眼
Now you've come to me at last,
<i>现在你最终到了我这</i>
Brandon Stark.
布兰登·史塔克
Though the hour is late.
尽管迟了点
I didn't want anyone to die for me.
我不想任何人为我而死
He died so you could find what you have lost.
他死了你才能找到你丢失的东西
You're going to help me walk again?
你想帮我再次走路？
You will never walk again.
<i>你不会再走路了</i>
But you will fly.
但是你会飞翔
Podrick.
波德瑞克
Where are the horses?
马在哪里？
I hobbled them last night.
我昨晚把马绑上了
What sort of hobble?
怎么绑的？
A figure eight like you taught me.
八字结，按你教我那样
If you did it like I taught you,
如果你按我教你那样绑的
then the horses would be here.
那马应该还在这
Thieves, maybe?
也许有小偷？
It's at least 30 miles to the Eyrie from here.
鹰巢城离这至少30里地
You're carrying the saddlebags.
行李你背
People coming.
有人来了
You can shit later. There's people coming.
你等会再拉，有人来了
Morning.
早上好
I like your sword.
剑不错
Are we getting close to the Bloody Gate?
<i>这离血门还远吗？</i>
About 10 more miles.
再走大约10里
Did you hear that, Podrick?
听到了没有，波德瑞克？
Only 10 more miles to the Bloody Gate.
再走10里就到血门了
Are you a knight?
你是骑士吗？
No.
不是
But you know how to use that sword?
但你会使剑？
I do.
会
Does it have a name?
剑叫什么？
Oathkeeper.
守誓剑
Mine's Needle.
我的剑叫缝衣针
Good name.
名字不错
Who taught you how to fight?
谁教你战斗的？
My father.
我父亲
Mine never wanted to.
我父亲从不想让我学
Said fighting was for boys.
他说战斗是男孩子的事
Mine said the same.
我父亲也这么说
But I kept fighting the boys anyway.
但我还是继续跟男孩战斗
Kept losing.
<i>总是输</i>
Finally my father said, "If you're going to do it,
最后，我父亲说：“要战斗的话”
you might as well do it right."
“还是像样学学吧”
Seven blessings.
七神保佑
I'm Brienne of Tarth. This is Podrick Payne.
我是塔斯的布蕾妮，他是波德瑞克·派恩
You want something?
你想干什么？
That's Sandor Clegane. The Hound.
他是桑铎·克里冈，“猎狗”
You're Arya Stark.
你是艾莉亚·史塔克
I asked if you wanted something.
我问你想干什么？
I swore to your mother I would bring you home to her.
我向你母亲发誓，会带你回家见她
My mother's dead.
我母亲死了
I know.
<i>我知道</i>
I wish I could have been there to protect her.
我只恨没能在她身边保护她
You're not a northerner.
你不是北境人
No, but I swore a sacred vow to protect her.
不是，但我立下了神圣誓言要保护她
Why didn't you?
那你怎么不保护她？
She commanded me to bring Jaime Lannister back to King's Landing.
她命令我带詹姆·兰尼斯特回君临城
You're paid by the Lannisters.
你收了兰尼斯特的钱
You're here for the bounty on me.
<i>你是来杀我领赏金的</i>
I'm not paid by the Lannisters.
我没收兰尼斯特的钱
No?
没有？
Fancy sword you've got there.
剑不错啊
Where'd you get it?
哪来的？
I've been looking at Lannister gold all my life.
兰尼斯特的金子我看了一辈子
Go on, Brienne of fucking Tarth.
说吧，什么狗屁塔斯的布蕾妮
Tell me that's not Lannister gold.
说这不是兰尼斯特的金子
Jaime Lannister gave me this sword.
这剑是詹姆·兰尼斯特送我的
The Bloody Gate is 10 miles.
血门还有10里
I swore to your mother by the old gods--
我向你母亲发誓，以旧神…
I don't care what you swore.
我不管你发了什么誓
- Arya! - You heard the girl.
- 艾莉亚！
<i>- 你听见了</i>
- She's not coming with you. - She is.
- 她不会跟你走的
- 她会的
You're not a good listener.
你没听清楚吧
That Valyrian steel?
瓦雷利亚钢？
I always wanted some Valyrian steel.
我一直想弄点瓦雷利亚钢
Come with me, Arya. I'll take you to safety.
跟我走，艾莉亚，我会带你到安全的地方
Safety? Where the fuck's that?
安全的地方？那他妈是哪？
Her aunt in the Eyrie is dead. Her mother's dead.
她在鹰巢城的姨妈死了，她母亲死了
Her father's dead. Her brother's dead.
她父亲死了，她哥哥死了
Winterfell is a pile of rubble.
临冬城成了乱石堆了
There is no safety, you dumb bitch.
没有安全的地方，你个傻婊子
You don't know that by now,
你还不明白吗？
you're the wrong one to watch over her.
她不应该由你来照顾
And that's what you're doing?
那应该由你来？
Watching over her?
照顾她？
Aye, that's what I'm doing.
是，现在我在照顾她
I have no wish to kill you, Ser.
我不想杀你，爵士
I'm not a knight.
我不是骑士
Arya!
艾莉亚！
- Where is she? - She was just here.
- 她去哪了？
<i>- 刚才就在这</i>
Why weren't you watching her?
你为什么不看着她？
I was watching you. I thought you might need some help.
我在看着你，我以为你会需要支援
Which way, Pod? Which way did she go?
哪边，波德？她往哪边走了？
I think that way.
可能是那边
Arya!
<i>艾莉亚！</i>
You still here?
你还在这？
Big bitch saved you.
大个婊子救了你
I don't need saving.
我不用人救
No, not you. You're a real killer.
你确实不用，你是真正的杀手
With your water dancing
会跳水之舞
and your Needle.
还有缝衣针
You gonna die?
你会死吗？
Unless there's a maester hiding behind that rock,
除非石头后面藏着个学士
aye,
是的
I'm done.
我完了
I'd skin you alive for wine.
现在要是能有酒，让我活剥了你都行
Fuck water.
去他妈的水
Killed by a woman.
居然被女人杀了
I bet you like that.
你肯定喜欢
Go on,
去吧
go after her.
跟她走吧
She'll help you.
<i>她会帮你</i>
Going it alone,
独自在外
you won't last a day out there.
<i>你一天都活不了</i>
I'll last longer than you.
我会活得比你久的
You remember where the heart is?
还记得心脏在哪吗？
Fuck it.
去他的
I'm ready.
我准备好了
Go on, girl.
来吧，小妞
Another name off your list.
名单上再划掉一个名字吧
You kept promising me.
你总说会杀我
I cut down your butcher's boy.
我砍死了屠夫的儿子
The ginger.
红头发那个
He was begging for mercy.
他求我饶命
"Please, Ser. Please don't kill me.
“求您了，爵士，求您别杀我”
Please, please."
“求求您了”
Bled all over my horse.
<i>血溅了我的马一身</i>
Saddle stunk of butcher's boy for weeks.
<i>好几个星期马鞍都是他的臭味</i>
And your sister.
还有你姐姐
Your pretty sister.
你漂亮的姐姐
I should have taken her.
<i>我应该干了她</i>
That night the Blackwater burned.
黑水河燃烧那夜
I should have fucked her bloody.
我应该狠狠地操她
At least I'd have one happy memory.
<i>至少也能有一段快乐的回忆</i>
Do I have to beg you?
要我求你吗？
Do it.
动手吧
动手啊
Kill me.
杀了我
Kill me!
杀了我！
杀了我吧！
Kill me!
杀了我啊！
Oh, get on with it, you son of a whore.
噢，要杀就杀吧，狗娘养的
Is that any way to speak about our mother?
你都管我们母亲叫狗娘？
What are you doing?
你在干嘛？
What do you think I'm doing?
你觉得我在干嘛？
A galley's waiting in the bay bound for the Free Cities.
港口里有帆船接应，去自由贸易城邦
- Who's helping you? - Varys.
- 谁帮你找的？
- 瓦里斯
- Varys? - You have more friends than you thought.
- 瓦里斯？
- 你的朋友比你想的多
There's a locked door at the top of the stairs.
台阶顶上有一扇锁着的门
Knock on it twice, then twice again.
敲两下，然后再敲两下
Varys will open.
瓦里斯会开门
I suppose this is good-bye, then.
那这就是告别了
Farewell, little brother.
永别了，弟弟
Jaime.
詹姆
Thank you for my life.
你的恩情，今生感激不尽
Quickly now.
快走吧
Tywin?
泰温？
My lion.
我的狮子
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Tyrion.
提里昂
Put down the crossbow.
放下十字弓
Who released you?
谁把你放了？
Your brother, I expect.
我猜是你哥哥
He always had a soft spot for you.
他总是对你心软
Come, we'll go and talk in my chambers.
走，去我屋里谈
This is how you want to speak to me, hmm?
你就想这样跟我谈？
Shaming your father has always given you pleasure.
<i>亏你父亲还一直哄你开心</i>
All my life
我这一生
you've wanted me dead.
你一直想让我死
Yes.
没错
But you refused to die.
<i>但你不想死</i>
I respect that.
我尊敬你
Even admire it.
甚至敬佩你
You fight for what's yours.
<i>你全力为自己争取</i>
I'd never let them execute you.
我不会让他们处决你的
Is that what you fear?
你是在怕这个吗？
I'll never let Ilyn Payne take your head.
<i>我不会让伊林·派恩砍你的头的</i>
You're a Lannister.
你是兰尼斯特
You're my son.
你是我儿子
I loved her.
我爱过她
Who?
谁？
Shae.
雪伊
Oh, Tyrion.
得了，提里昂
- Put down that crossbow. - I murdered her.
- 放下十字弓
- 我杀了她
With my own hands.
亲手杀的
- It doesn't matter. - Doesn't matter?
- 那不重要
- 不重要？
She was a whore.
她是个妓女
- Say that word again... - And what?
- 再说这话我就…
- <i>就怎样？</i>
You'll kill your own father in the privy?
在厕所里杀了你父亲？
No.
你不会
You're my son.
你是我儿子
Now, enough of this nonsense.
好了，闹够了
I am your son and you sentenced me to die.
我是你儿子，而你判我死刑
You knew I didn't poison Joffrey,
你明知我没给乔佛里下毒
but you sentenced me all the same.
但你还是判我死刑
- Why? - Enough.
- 为什么？
- 够了
We'll go back to my chambers
<i>回我房间</i>
and speak with some dignity.
有点尊严再谈
I can't go back there. She's in there.
我不能回去，她在那
You're afraid of a dead whore?
你怕死妓女？
You shot me.
你居然朝我射箭
You're no son of mine.
你不是我儿子
I am your son.
我是你儿子
I have always been your son.
我永远都是你儿子
What have you done?
你干什么去了？
Quickly.
快走
Trust me, my friend. I brought you this far.
相信我，朋友，事已至此了
I want to see the captain.
我要见船长
You're seeing him.
我就是
I want to go north to the Wall.
我想向北，去长城
No, you don't.
你不能去
I can pay.
我可以付钱
There is nothing in the North but ice and war and pirates.
北境只有冰、战争和海盗
I wouldn't need a cabin. Please.
我不占船舱，求您了
I could work scrubbing the floors.
我可以干活，擦甲板
I'm not going north, child. I'm going home.
我不去北境，孩子，我要回家
- Where's home? - The Free City of Braavos.
- 你家在哪？
- 布拉佛斯的自由城邦
Wait. I have something else.
等等，我还有别的
More silver won't make a difference.
再多银子也没用
It's not silver. It's iron.
不是银子，是铁
This...
这…
How did you--
你怎么会…
Valar morghulis.
<i>Valar morghulis（凡人皆有一死）</i>
Valar dohaeris.
<i>Valar dohaeris（凡人皆需侍奉）</i>
Of course, you shall have a cabin.
没问题，你可以住一间船舱
-=TLF字幕组=-
谢谢观赏
TLF中文字幕站 http://sub.eastgame.org/
微博地址：http://weibo.com/tlfsubs
豆瓣小站：http://site.douban.com/127446/